

HARI PRAKASH - Senior Business Analyst

Chennai, India

+91 9003028561

hari20prakash@gmail.com

n /hari-prakash-rao

As a well-organized Business Analyst/Proxy Product Owner with 7.5 years of experience responsible in identifying and define the PLM solutions that will maximize the value delivery using Business intelligence and data visualization tools to create actionable reports. All work is done in agile teams is iterative collaboration with developers. Acting as role model in all activities required to reach customer satisfaction. Having ambition to work with business requirement breakdown development.

Certifications

- Salesforce Business Analyst Salesforce, Aug 2023
- Certified Product
 Owner/Product Manager
 Scaled Agile, April 2023
- Certified Professional Scrum
 Product Owner 1
 Scrum.org, April 2023
- Certified Professional Scrum
 Master 1
 Scrum.org, April 2023
- Salesforce Administrator
 Salesforce, June 2022
 Learnt Objects, bulding relationship
 between object & different Data
 type field creation
- Master Diploma CAD
 CADD Centre, April 2008

AutoCAD 2D & 3D drawings in Pro-E, Modelling in Solidworks ,Catia & NX

Primavera P6 Enterprise Project
 Portfolio Management
 Implementation Specialist
 CADD Centre, Feb 2010

Initiation, Planning, Execution,
Performance monitoring and Closing
of the project

Professional Certificate Leading
 Innovation – Three Box Solution
 edX, Dec 2021

Box 1: Manage the present. Box 2: Selectively forget the past.

Box 3: Create the future

Work Experience

Assistant Manager - Agile Lead Business Analyst / Proxy Product Owner

Renault Nissan Technology & Business Centre India - Oct 2016 - Present

- Requirement Analysis & solution design by actively discussion with Product owners
- Actively engaged with Business partners to derive detailed solutions
- Defined conditions of acceptance criteria and creating BRD,FRD, Wireframes
- Ensured that the product backlog is visible to the entire team
- Supported the team in understanding the user stories and the business values it imparts
- Executed delegate Product Ownership in the Agile team methodologies
- Responsible for planning, organizing, reporting, and following up the requirement activities in accordance with the development SDLC processes
- Engaging with UI-UX team to discuss and enhance user experience
- Working with solution implementation team for story grooming, PBI tracking, UAT
- Assisting team during UAT to identify Change Request Vs Bugs
- Managed the development and enhancements of PLM Platforms to implementation
- Possessed enough knowledge to troubleshoot Siemens Teamcenter errors in design part

Research and Innovation Management

Renault Nissan Technology & Business Centre India - Oct 2014 - Sep 2016 - 2yrs

- Managed Innovation Database through CFT Collaboration Engagement
- Identified mentorship Program and PoC status
- Screened & mentored with HODs & maintain Documentation
- Facilitated Budget Management integration with i-QMS Documentation
- Led yearly update of Innovation framework based on strategic direction
- Managed the tool, Documentation, Identifying mentorship Program and PoC

Product Lifecycle Management Specialist

Renault Nissan Technology & Business Centre India - Oct 2012 - Sep 2014 · 2 yrs.

- Supported as Technical Documentation Leader in Design Administration Management
- Analyzed the ECM, ECR, BOM, NPD and Release Management
- Identified potential new projects, coordinated production releases
- Consistently met deadlines with team Project Management
- Performed Teamcenter POCs (Proof of Concept) based on Business and Technical cases
- Contributed Vehicle Planning for New models & Existing models through G2B and BOM
- Liaised with stakeholders to identify requirements
- Engineering Design Release process at all stages of vehicle development.

Senior Product Design Engineer

GGS Information Services - Feb 2011 - Oct 2012 · 1 yrs. 9 months

- Provided Technical Data for Releasing the Completed Drawing files in as per CAT Standards
- Handled the Customer ECOs/ECN/Drawings closely and coordinate
- Performed Well versed in ERP to update and maintain BOM accuracy
- Implemented the Pro-E generated drawing into the Team Center Enterprise

Mechanical Design Engineer

Johnson Lifts & Escalators – June 2008 - Feb 2011 · 2 yrs. 9 months

- General Assembly Drawings 2D & 3D AutoCAD
- Visualized the economical method of manufacturing detail Components & Assemblies
- Solved problems by multiple tasks connected to project on time
 - Acquired & Developed the Elevator general arrangement Planning Drawing

Skills

Technical Skills

- AutoCAD Drafting & Modelling
- Salesforce Administrator
- Visio
- PLM Team center
- Analysis Skills
- SDLC
- Jira
- Sharepoint
- Confluence
- UML Diagrams
- Balsamiq Wireframes
- Figma Design
- Adobe XD design
- MS Visio

Project Management

- Project planning
- Risk Management
- Documentation MS office

On-site Exposure:

Senior Product Specialist @Nissan Motor Corporation

Jan 2013 - Mar 2013 · 3 mos

Atsugi, Kanagawa, Japan

Languages:

English, Tamil, Hindi, Marathi

Interest:

- Work to improve certain business practices.
- Helping people around
- Generating Innovative ideas
- Collaborate with a team for upskilling.

Education

Master of Business Administration, Project Management Alagappa University – 2017 – 2019

B.Tech Mechanical Engineering

Karnataka State Open University - 2010 - 2014

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering

Sriram Polytechnic College – 2005 – 2008

12th State Board – Computer Science Department

Bhaktavatsalam Vidyashram - 2004 - 2005

10th Standard CBSE Syllabus

G.K. Shetty Vivekananda Vidyalaya Junior College - 2003

Awards

- ✓ Dec 2022: Annual Award 2021 | Innovation Management
- ✓ Mar 2022: Vice President Award -Innovation Club
- ✓ Jun 2012: G2B System Checker Nissan Specific Technology
- ✓ Apr 2018: Best Individual Award -PLM
- ✓ May 2018: Best Team Award FTR & OTD 100% Achieved